<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2020-05-01T21:33:27+01:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/</id><title type="html">DevPractical</title><subtitle>Practical tips for Developers, from a developer.</subtitle><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><entry><title type="html">Adaptability: an overlooked virtue</title><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/non_technical/2020/04/29/adaptability-an-overlooked-virtue/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adaptability: an overlooked virtue" /><published>2020-04-29T21:28:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-29T21:28:00+01:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/non_technical/2020/04/29/adaptability-an-overlooked-virtue</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nickwu007.github.io/non_technical/2020/04/29/adaptability-an-overlooked-virtue/">&lt;p&gt;It has been since I sat down to write an article properly, since most of my off-work time has been put into my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLfkNBxEf3tVFjCJQ67ofI2Wh5yQwPGxOn&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;. With the lockdown situation continuing for the foreseeable future, production has been a bit more difficult, so I thought I give the good old blogging another shot. This week I want to discuss &lt;em&gt;adaptability&lt;/em&gt;, a virtue that I rarely see discussed in the industry and in my opinion absolutely essential to being a productive software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is a mix of my personal experiences and proper reasoning and arguments, which is how I like to write. That being said, I am sure not everyone is interested in my individual life, so feel free to skip past any anecdote and stories. And without further ado, let’s begin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-1&quot;&gt;How did I come across this?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-2&quot;&gt;“Sure, but why do I have to be adaptable?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-3&quot;&gt;Adaptability for software engineers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-5&quot;&gt;“Great! So how do I become more adaptable?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#chapter-6&quot;&gt;Closing words&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-i-come-across-this-&quot;&gt;How did I come across this? &lt;a name=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic of adaptability is by no means a sudden choice, and goes back to a couple years ago for me. In 2013 I was applying to various universities around the world, and one of the most common questions on the applications is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is your biggest strength?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a good few weeks thinking about this. Is it hardworking that helped my grades, or honesty that led me to good friends? I came up with more virtues as a 17-year-old possibly could, but none of them seemed to be the answer for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer came to me, as many others do, in the form of an episode of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quotes.net/mquote/884693&quot;&gt;The Big Bang Theory&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I am nothing if not adaptable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comic as it may be when Sheldon said it reacting to being pranked with unexpected dinner choice, I found this to be very true for myself. Moving to a city by myself a year earlier, I needed to adapt a lot to a new environment and lifestyle. And with the prospect of moving again for uni, I felt like my ability to get comfortable and productive were the best edge I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consciously or otherwise, the following few years did prove exactly that. I have moved a few more times for various reasons, and I can confidently say that I have adapted to each to the best of my abilities. Recently I came across a post about &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/demianbrecht/dude-i-m-slagging-your-code-not-you-4nja&quot;&gt;taking feedback in code reviews&lt;/a&gt;, and added a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/nickwu007/comment/o7i5&quot;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; about how I adapted to it since I started working full time as a software engineer. With this tiny reminder, I felt like it was time to offer my own two cents with a proper post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/time-for-change.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Time for change!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sure-but-why-do-i-have-to-be-adaptable-&quot;&gt;“Sure, but why do I have to be adaptable?” &lt;a name=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-only-natural&quot;&gt;It’s only natural&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before getting into detail about how adaptability is crucial in the tech industry, there is a fundamental point to made here. Humans, or any other organisms for that matter, have been adapting for as long as history can tell: “Survival of the fittest”. We are always adapting to the situation, and changing our ways to make the best of things. Adaptability isn’t a special skill that you have to learn; everyone has it already. It’s only natural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-tech-world-changes-too-often&quot;&gt;The tech world changes too often&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a software engineer, we have all heard and experienced how fast and drastically the tech world changes (remember when you have to &lt;em&gt;dial the phone to get on the Internet&lt;/em&gt;?). Languages, frameworks, technologies come and go all the time. Sooner or later, you come to a point where what you know isn’t useful anymore. As Albert Einstein &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/85475-the-measure-of-intelligence-is-the-ability-to-change&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The measure of intelligence is the ability to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, for the longest time I thought a backend server is where you put your business logic, and there is no other way. When I approach a new project, I always put up a server in some VM, and it just felt right. Then a couple years ago, SaaS (Software as a Service) came out of nowhere for me. Suddenly you can just write individual functions and expose them to your client, without the form of a server at all. I couldn’t not see the benefits of this approach, and gradually shifted my thinking to that. Painful as it was in the beginning, this went on to boost my productivity to a whole new level. Adapt yourself my friend, there’s always fruit for your labour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/change-sign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Changes abound&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adaptability-as-software-engineers-&quot;&gt;Adaptability as software engineers &lt;a name=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope now you are more convinced about the usefulness of being adaptable. But what does it mean to be an “adaptable software engineer”? This is by no means a complete list, but what I consider the strongest indicators from other engineers that I look up to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mindful-of-constraints&quot;&gt;Mindful of constraints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software is written to solve problems, and there are many ways to solve the same problem. An adaptable engineer is aware of the particular constraints of the problem: latency, computing resources, or even availability of the team. With this in mind they move to find the best option that suits these constraints. Most of the time these constraints pop up unexpectedly, and they must quickly understand them, and readjust to make sure nothing blows up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shifting-technical-thinking&quot;&gt;Shifting technical thinking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software development is a bigger field than most of us realize, and you will encounter problems in areas that you probably did not know existed before. An adaptable engineer is able to shift their technical mindset into a particular field, and analyze the problem in the appropriate domain language. If it is a user interface problem, then they think in a matter of time and events. If the problem is about complex logic, they think in a matter of data and flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wear-many-hats&quot;&gt;Wear many hats&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code is only one thing that we interact with day-to-day; there are also other engineers, designers, users, and many more. An adaptable engineer is able to communicate to each front in an effective way, acting as a interpreter of sort. They understand what users want, and translate it into hard logic to machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;not-always-passive&quot;&gt;Not always passive&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adapting seems like a reactionary action, but the truth is far from it. An adaptable engineer keeps a keen eye for improvements, whether it is code or the product. They know that adapting does not only happen in the dark days, and in fact continuous improvements is a better route to success than a pinch overhaul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-so-how-do-i-become-more-adaptable-&quot;&gt;“Great! So how do I become more adaptable?” &lt;a name=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe one does not become adaptable in a day, and many of these indicators seem too hard to achieve. Honestly, I am also in the very early stage of my career, and I have no clue how one stays adaptable 10 years down the line, having moved from position to position. But below are a few advice that I have, many of which were given to me by the best engineers that I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-be-afraid-to-change&quot;&gt;Don’t be afraid to change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first and the most important principle of being adaptable is willing to do so. Way too often we hung on to our intellectual products, because we thought and worked hard for it. As Adam Hunt wrote in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4099.The_Pragmatic_Programmer&quot;&gt;The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The greatest of all weaknesses is the fear of appearing weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like the post that inspired this one, the code that we wrote does not always represent us as engineers. The decisions we made earlier might not be the best now, most of the time through no fault of our own. Rather than disregarding the risks and persistently sticking to our guts, we might have a better chance if we listened and adjusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/open-sign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Be open for change my friend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-your-eye-at-the-goal&quot;&gt;Keep your eye at the goal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cliche phase I know, but I have found this be a incredibly useful principle for calibrating yourself. When you are presented with a problem, understand the core of the problem itself. And when you are trying to solve it, and having to adapt to various constraints, always remember whatever you shift to do should help you get closer to solving the core problem. In the past I have had episodes where I tried to change direction when hitting a roadblock, forgot what I needed to solve in the first place, and ended up with something totally unusable. Don’t make my mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;do-it-often&quot;&gt;Do it often&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inertia is an ironically powerful force. You should be looking out for opportunities for adjustments, rather than being forced to one when your car has metaphorically ground to a halt. A useful tip that I have adopted is having sync with manager/colleague periodically (weekly or bi-weekly for me), in which I talk about my recent productivity, what’s lacking, what’s coming my way, and how I should adapt. If I ask for advice, more or less we can come up with a few things to change, and over time I have grown to a better engineer because of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing-words-&quot;&gt;Closing words &lt;a name=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this post has given you a think about adaptability as a software engineer. In my opinion this is one of the most productive qualities one can cultivate. If you have any thoughts and experience, I would love to hear about them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you click out, I want to leave you with a quote from Bruce Lee, one of my personal idols:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You must be shapeless, formless, like water. When you pour water in a cup, it becomes the cup. When you pour water in a bottle, it becomes the bottle. When you pour water in a teapot, it becomes the teapot. Water can drip and it can crash. Become like water my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><summary type="html">It has been since I sat down to write an article properly, since most of my off-work time has been put into my podcast. With the lockdown situation continuing for the foreseeable future, production has been a bit more difficult, so I thought I give the good old blogging another shot. This week I want to discuss adaptability, a virtue that I rarely see discussed in the industry and in my opinion absolutely essential to being a productive software engineer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nickwu007.github.io/assets/images/adaptability-cover.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Compile Podcast Ep 15: Adaptability: an overlooked virtue</title><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/24/compile-15/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compile Podcast Ep 15: Adaptability: an overlooked virtue" /><published>2020-04-24T21:28:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-24T21:28:00+01:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/24/compile-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/24/compile-15/">&lt;p&gt;This week I talk about adaptability as a software engineer, from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://nickwu007.github.io/non_technical/2020/04/29/adaptability-an-overlooked-virtue/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; that I wrote earlier this week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakpoints&quot;&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;00:50 Topic intro: adaptability as a software engineer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;01:33 How did I come across this?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;03:27 “Sure, but why do I have to be adaptable?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;05:18 Adaptability as software engineers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;07:37 “Great! So how do I become more adaptable?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10:20 Closing words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;links-in-this-episode&quot;&gt;Links in this episode:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quote from the Big Bang Theory: https://www.quotes.net/mquote/884693&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interesting post about taking feedback in code reviews: https://dev.to/demianbrecht/dude-i-m-slagging-your-code-not-you-4nja&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quote from Albert Einstein: https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/85475-the-measure-of-intelligence-is-the-ability-to-change&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quote from Adam Hunt in The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master: https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4099.The_Pragmatic_Programmer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reach-out-to-us&quot;&gt;Reach out to us!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe and stay tuned! Also send in any comment or request for new topics and we will try our best to make them happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Twitter: https://twitter.com/WujunaoNick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Podcast is also on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen#/ps/Ifd5mlxhgc5cmlsytadsglqfd4y&quot;&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-compile-podcast/id1436437367&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2UH9hK7VlS7ytjYdM8Vd78&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><summary type="html">This week I talk about adaptability as a software engineer, from a blog post that I wrote earlier this week!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nickwu007.github.io/assets/images/compile_ep_15.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Compile Podcast Ep 14: First year of code</title><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/24/compile-14/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compile Podcast Ep 14: First year of code" /><published>2020-04-24T21:28:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-24T21:28:00+01:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/24/compile-14</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/24/compile-14/">&lt;p&gt;This week Brennan joins me again to talk about our first year of coding professionally, our experiences and thoughts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reach-out-to-us&quot;&gt;Reach out to us!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe and stay tuned! Also send in any comment or request for new topics and we will try our best to make them happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Twitter: https://twitter.com/WujunaoNick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Podcast is also on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen#/ps/Ifd5mlxhgc5cmlsytadsglqfd4y&quot;&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-compile-podcast/id1436437367&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2UH9hK7VlS7ytjYdM8Vd78&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><summary type="html">This week Brennan joins me again to talk about our first year of coding professionally, our experiences and thoughts!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nickwu007.github.io/assets/images/compile_ep_14.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Compile Podcast Ep 13: Learning a programming language</title><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/13/compile-13/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compile Podcast Ep 13: Learning a programming language" /><published>2020-04-13T11:08:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-13T11:08:00+01:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/13/compile-13</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/13/compile-13/">&lt;p&gt;This week Jasper and I talk about our experiences in learning programming languages, and how you can pick up a new programming language during the quarantine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakpoints&quot;&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;00:00 Chill zone and catching up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;02:14 why learn a programming language&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;16:33 How do we learn new languages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;36:19 Wrapping up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reach-out-to-us&quot;&gt;Reach out to us!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe and stay tuned! Also send in any comment or request for new topics and we will try our best to make them happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Twitter: https://twitter.com/WujunaoNick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Podcast is also on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen#/ps/Ifd5mlxhgc5cmlsytadsglqfd4y&quot;&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-compile-podcast/id1436437367&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2UH9hK7VlS7ytjYdM8Vd78&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><summary type="html">This week Jasper and I talk about our experiences in learning programming languages, and how you can pick up a new programming language during the quarantine!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nickwu007.github.io/assets/images/compile_ep_13.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Compile Podcast Ep 12: How to avoid quarantine gut?</title><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/10/compile-12/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compile Podcast Ep 12: How to avoid quarantine gut?" /><published>2020-04-10T20:50:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-10T20:50:00+01:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/10/compile-12</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/10/compile-12/">&lt;p&gt;This week my friend Yuekun and I talk more about maintaining a healthy diet during the quarantine, and how to avoid getting a quarantine gut!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakpoints&quot;&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;00:32 Chill zone and catching up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;07:26 Topic intro: how to avoid quarantine gut&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12:50 A balanced diet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;16:50 “Eat your vegetables”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;19:30 Yuekun recommends a few staple vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;38:38 How to correctly limit total caloric intake&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;44:45 Enjoy your food&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;47:41 Counting calories work, but don’t count on it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;53:46 Consider using supplements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;57:58 Wrapping up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;links-in-this-episode&quot;&gt;Links in this episode:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BtulL3oArQw&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; from Vietnam about Covid-19&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yuekun’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/that_chinese_guy_&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reach-out-to-us&quot;&gt;Reach out to us!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe and stay tuned! Also send in any comment or request for new topics and we will try our best to make them happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Twitter: https://twitter.com/WujunaoNick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Podcast is also on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen#/ps/Ifd5mlxhgc5cmlsytadsglqfd4y&quot;&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-compile-podcast/id1436437367&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2UH9hK7VlS7ytjYdM8Vd78&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><summary type="html">This week my friend Yuekun and I talk more about maintaining a healthy diet during the quarantine, and how to avoid getting a quarantine gut!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nickwu007.github.io/assets/images/compile_ep_12.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Compile Podcast Ep 11: Can WFH be productive?</title><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/03/compile-11/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compile Podcast Ep 11: Can WFH be productive?" /><published>2020-04-03T21:29:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-04-03T21:29:00+01:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/03/compile-11</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/04/03/compile-11/">&lt;p&gt;This week my good friend John joins me again to talk about how to be productive while Working from home during the times of quarantine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakpoints&quot;&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;00:42 Chill zone and catching up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;02:45 Topic intro: productivity while working from home&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;03:20 Our WFH experiences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10:35 Establish a clean cut between work and life
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;16:08 Having a dedicated work area&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;19:40 Get some fresh air/change of scenery&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;23:05 Keep your work routine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;25:35 Take a breather before starting work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;28:58 Our typical work day during the quarantine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;35:00 Get your remote toolkit ready&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;44:15 Be social and avoid loniness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;46:34 Distractions and how to moderate them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;54:09 “Compile” time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reach-out-to-us&quot;&gt;Reach out to us!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe and stay tuned! Also send in any comment or request for new topics and we will try our best to make them happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Twitter: https://twitter.com/WujunaoNick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Podcast is also on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen#/ps/Ifd5mlxhgc5cmlsytadsglqfd4y&quot;&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-compile-podcast/id1436437367&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2UH9hK7VlS7ytjYdM8Vd78&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><summary type="html">This week my good friend John joins me again to talk about how to be productive while Working from home during the times of quarantine!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nickwu007.github.io/assets/images/compile_ep_11.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Compile Podcast Ep 10: Staying fit at home</title><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/28/compile-10/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compile Podcast Ep 10: Staying fit at home" /><published>2020-03-28T09:31:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-28T09:31:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/28/compile-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/28/compile-10/">&lt;p&gt;This week my friend Yuekun and I talk more about fitness at home and how you can avoid “isolation gut”!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakpoints&quot;&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;01:00 Chill zone and catching up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;05:00 Topic intro: staying fit at home&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;07:20 Why staying fit is so important, especially now
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;08:25 A Strong immune system&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;11:40 Nick’s experience with momentum and inertia&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;16:17 Lack of activity leads to general health problems&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;26:42 Yuekun’s very own exercise routines
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;29:41 Stretches&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;37:20 How to get a good stretch?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;39:00 Slow steady cardio&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;42:21 Basic and intermediate workouts&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;45:00 Results with the routines for Yuekun’s parents&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;49:19 Nick and Yuekun share their current routines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;56:43 Wrapping up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;links-in-this-episode&quot;&gt;Links in this episode:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BtN-goy9VOY&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; that explains Coronavirus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://compilepodcast.s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/Easy+At-Home+Exercises.pdf&quot;&gt;Home exercise routines&lt;/a&gt; designed by Yuekun himself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yuekun’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/that_chinese_guy_&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reach-out-to-us&quot;&gt;Reach out to us!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe and stay tuned! Also send in any comment or request for new topics and we will try our best to make them happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Twitter: https://twitter.com/WujunaoNick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Podcast is also on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen#/ps/Ifd5mlxhgc5cmlsytadsglqfd4y&quot;&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-compile-podcast/id1436437367&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2UH9hK7VlS7ytjYdM8Vd78&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><summary type="html">This week my friend Yuekun and I talk more about fitness at home and how you can avoid &quot;isolation gut&quot;!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nickwu007.github.io/assets/images/compile_ep_10.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Compile Podcast Ep 9: Workout and Productivity</title><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/20/compile-9/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compile Podcast Ep 9: Workout and Productivity" /><published>2020-03-20T22:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-20T22:16:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/20/compile-9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/20/compile-9/">&lt;p&gt;This week my friend Yuekun and I talk about working out and how it impacts your productivity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakpoints&quot;&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;00:00 A little foreword&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;01:00 Podcast Intro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;02:25 What happens when you don’t work out
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;02:54 Prone to chronical injuries&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;04:03 Mental stress from getting stuck at work&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;05:16 Lack of discipline and confidence&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;07:25 “Does working out make you more tired actually?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;09:19 Benefits to productivity from working out
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;09:53 It is important to spend some time away from work&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;10:08 Science of health benefits&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;11:37 Nick’s personal journey of working out&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;13:29 Benefits to developers&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;18:32 Discovering hidden points&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;21:35 Cultivate a healthy respect to time management and building habits&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;27:54 What time of day would be the best for workout if you have live a 9-5 life?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;37:56 Wrapping up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reach-out-to-us&quot;&gt;Reach out to us!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe and stay tuned! Also send in any comment or request for new topics and we will try our best to make them happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Twitter: https://twitter.com/WujunaoNick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Podcast is also on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen#/ps/Ifd5mlxhgc5cmlsytadsglqfd4y&quot;&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-compile-podcast/id1436437367&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2UH9hK7VlS7ytjYdM8Vd78&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><summary type="html">This week my friend Yuekun and I talk about working out and how it impacts your productivity!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nickwu007.github.io/assets/images/compile_ep_9.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Compile Podcast Ep 8: Anxiety – How to deal with it?</title><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/13/compile-8/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compile Podcast Ep 8: Anxiety -- How to deal with it?" /><published>2020-03-13T21:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-13T21:04:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/13/compile-8</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/13/compile-8/">&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode Jasper and I talk about our experiences with anxiety, and tips about dealing with it mentally and practically!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakpoints&quot;&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;00:25 Chill zone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;07:20 Mindset towards stress and anxiety
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;08:55 “Everyone has it”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;11:35 Acknowledge your anxiety&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;14:44 Find out the root of stress&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;21:30 “It’s not the end of the world”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;23:00 “Don’t suffer twice”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;24:25 “You will not remember what you were worried about last week”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;28:40 Practical tips to deal with anxiety
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;28:58 Breathing exercise&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;33:40 Find distraction and keep busy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;38:05 Talk about your anxiety&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;41:15 Don’t be afraid to seek help&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;42:25 “Running away is shameful, but useful” (use with caution)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;45:45 “Compile” time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;46:34 Personal favourite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;links-in-this-episode&quot;&gt;Links in this episode:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The art of breathing” by Dr Danny Penman: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Art-Breathing-Dr-Danny-Penman/dp/0008206619&quot;&gt;amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2234155/&quot;&gt;“The Internship” movie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hungarian proverb: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nigeru_wa_Haji_da_ga_Yaku_ni_Tatsu&quot;&gt;“Running away is shameful, but useful”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reach-out-to-us&quot;&gt;Reach out to us!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe and stay tuned! Also send in any comment or request for new topics and we will try our best to make them happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Twitter: https://twitter.com/WujunaoNick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Podcast is also on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen#/ps/Ifd5mlxhgc5cmlsytadsglqfd4y&quot;&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-compile-podcast/id1436437367&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2UH9hK7VlS7ytjYdM8Vd78&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><summary type="html">Jasper and I talk about our experiences with anxiety, and tips about dealing with it mentally and practically!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nickwu007.github.io/assets/images/compile_ep_8.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Compile Podcast Ep 7: Hobbies – What we do when we are not working</title><link href="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/07/compile-7/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compile Podcast Ep 7: Hobbies -- What we do when we are not working" /><published>2020-03-07T20:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-07T20:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/07/compile-7</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://nickwu007.github.io/podcast/2020/03/07/compile-7/">&lt;p&gt;In this week’s episode Jasper and I talk about our hobbies when we are not coding, and what you can do to find a hobby for yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breakpoints&quot;&gt;Breakpoints&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;00:58 Why is a hobby important, espeically for a developer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11:27 How do I go about finding a hobby?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;21:17 Jasper and I talk about our hobbies
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;21:25 Technical hobbies&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;28:15 Non-technical hobbies&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;42:40 Wrap up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;links-in-this-episode&quot;&gt;Links in this episode:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Developer forum that I follow: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to&quot;&gt;dev.to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The Phoenix Project”: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/1942788290/ref=cm_sw_r_tw_dp_U_x_I7azEb7XA50C0&quot;&gt;amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.audible.co.uk/pd/The-Phoenix-Project-Audiobook/B00VB034GK&quot;&gt;audible book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recipe for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sortedfood.com/recipe/13950&quot;&gt;Chocolate Lava cake&lt;/a&gt; we made for In this week’s episode Jasper and I talk about our hobbies when we are not coding, and what you can do to find a hobby for yourself!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reach-out-to-us&quot;&gt;Reach out to us!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week we will have a new guest with a new topic! So subscribe and stay tuned! Also send in any comment or request for new topics and we will try our best to make them happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Twitter: https://twitter.com/WujunaoNick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Podcast is also on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/music/listen#/ps/Ifd5mlxhgc5cmlsytadsglqfd4y&quot;&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/the-compile-podcast/id1436437367&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2UH9hK7VlS7ytjYdM8Vd78&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Nick Wu</name></author><summary type="html">Jasper and I talk about our hobbies when we are not coding, and what you can do to find a hobby for yourself!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nickwu007.github.io/assets/images/compile_ep_7.png" /></entry></feed>